your assessments have been super helpful
I'm curious in keeping with the you know
the Jefferson haircut he famously had a
copy of Seneca on his nightstand and
when you chatted with John Verve a key
you mentioned that the collapse of
complex civilizations was in your top
five I'm curious what other books you
might be rereading or that you're
gifting out the most often to people
thanks well in imported materiality when
I packed up the RV and headed out to the
Texas Hill Country about six weeks ago I
did not pack many books with me so I
don't have any of them but let's go
hypothetically that's a really good
question
you know in the past not too long ago I
would tend to recommend books that were
let's call it educational I quite liked
carroll quigley his book the evolution
of civilizations for example I thought
he did a very thoughtful job about how
civilizations evolved and I've always
glued that together with dangerous stuff
and had that be a very powerful thing
Peter Turkmens works for example also
very very good but you know this is
Kairos it's really the time for that how
about I think it's called carnage and
culture have you ever heard of that
that's a pretty good one that's the
story about how how it is that for
whatever reason Western civilization
seem to always have this weird thing of
asymmetrically winning stuff they should
have lost over and over again which is
just talking about how do we pull that
off what is it what does it mean when
you're faced with absolutely
overwhelming odds and yet you're able to
pull off victory as the carnage and
culture is about and it talks about a
lot of the things that I've been talking
about here like how do we actually build
the capacity to have reasonable courage
and how do you know you can count on
that's kind of the stuff that I would
point to right now and I also take take
a look at deep mythopoetic archetypal
things because a lot of what's happening
right now can only be grasped through
that lens Arthurian legends and I don't
mean it in terms of entertainment I mean
now in terms of sacred texts like read
it and see where it lands in your body
where does that give you a signal of
what is something that needs that is
being called for now and by the way
who's mortared in this story
[Music]
you